<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>TTU Data Science League</title><link href="http://ttu-dsl.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ttu-dsl.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ttu-dsl.com/</id><updated>2019-02-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Kaggle Competitions</title><link href="http://ttu-dsl.com/kaggle-competitions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Nathan Martindale</name></author><id>tag:ttu-dsl.com,2019-02-26:/kaggle-competitions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As of our meeting today, we have officially started our inner-club kaggle
competitions. Everyone is invited to join in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ongoing competitions: &lt;strong&gt;project 0&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/c/titanic"&gt;titanic&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;strong&gt;project 1&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/c/house-prices-advanced-regression-techniques"&gt;house
prices&lt;/a&gt;.
Project 0 is intended for anyone new to data science. It's a relatively simple sample kaggle
competition, so …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As of our meeting today, we have officially started our inner-club kaggle
competitions. Everyone is invited to join in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ongoing competitions: &lt;strong&gt;project 0&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/c/titanic"&gt;titanic&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;strong&gt;project 1&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/c/house-prices-advanced-regression-techniques"&gt;house
prices&lt;/a&gt;.
Project 0 is intended for anyone new to data science. It's a relatively simple sample kaggle
competition, so it's a good place for people to become familiar with relevant
tools, basic DS concepts, and the procedure for participating in a kaggle
competition. Project 1 is a little bit more difficult, and a better place to
experiment with a wider variety of ML techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For both of these competitions, we have two teams: Team Cyan and Team Orange.
The competitions will run until our next meeting (one or two weeks after spring
break), at which point for each competition, whichever team has the highest
scoring submission will earn a small prize for each of its members. If you
didn't get a chance to come to the meeting to sign up, please feel free to
message me either on our discord server or shoot me an email at
namartinda42@students.tntech.edu. Let me know which project you'd like to work
on (you're absolutely allowed to work on both if you wish) and which team you
want to be part of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As new people join, I will add roles to your user on discord for your respective
project(s) and team - this will give you access to private chat groups for you
to discuss strategies, share code, and so forth. Similarly, once you're ready,
create a kaggle account and join the respective kaggle competitions above, and
send me your username. We will then add you to the correct kaggle team. (Orange
teams are being managed by Katie, and cyan teams are being managed by myself.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to message me with any questions or comments!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Kaggle API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the meeting I demoed the kaggle API, which allows you to interact with
kaggle from the commandline. This can be installed via: &lt;code&gt;pip install kaggle&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information can be found at &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kaggle/kaggle-api"&gt;their
github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>2/12/2019 Meeting Notes</title><link href="http://ttu-dsl.com/2122019-meeting-notes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-13T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Nathan Martindale</name></author><id>tag:ttu-dsl.com,2019-02-13:/2122019-meeting-notes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quick recap of what was covered at the meeting yesterday: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Club Status&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly we're unable to be an officially recognized student organization until we
can go before the student affairs people next September. We'll still be able to
meet in the meantime though, and pizza can be provided through the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quick recap of what was covered at the meeting yesterday: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Club Status&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly we're unable to be an officially recognized student organization until we
can go before the student affairs people next September. We'll still be able to
meet in the meantime though, and pizza can be provided through the department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Semester Plans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary focus I'm hoping to acheive this semester with DSL is on projects.
Doing is a great way of learning, so we'll be trying to compile a list of
projects to form teams around. Our meetings will
hopefully consist of discussion regarding progress on those projects, techniques
people have used, and possibly brief tutorials on things that may be useful in
current or future projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few different possible sources for projects. Dr. Gannod has
mentioned potentially connecting us with an athletics team, as well as other
people or departments who may have data they want explored. In addition, we can
play around with kaggle competitions - who knows, maybe someday we can attempt
an ongoing competition and submit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;ACM Webinar&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We watched a brief portion of an ACM seminar by Andrew Ng, covering tips for
going into a machine learning or data science oriented career. If anyone is
interested in watching the entire seminar, it can be found
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4kiHsIaK9_w"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Hello World!</title><link href="http://ttu-dsl.com/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-11T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Nathan Martindale</name></author><id>tag:ttu-dsl.com,2019-02-11:/hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Greetings to all! This is the first official post of our brand new website! This
post is simply to detail some of the things we hope to use this website for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As great as discord is as a means of communication, it's not a useful place to
try to aggregate …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Greetings to all! This is the first official post of our brand new website! This
post is simply to detail some of the things we hope to use this website for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As great as discord is as a means of communication, it's not a useful place to
try to aggregate interesting resources and tools related to this club. So,
perhaps one of the most useful functions for this website will be that we intend
to collect various data science and machine learning related resources (such
as places to get datasets, tutorials, interesting articles, etc.) and post them
to here, on the &lt;a href="resources.html"&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, as we start to get projects and such, this website can be a place
to organize information regarding those projects - whether it be to showcase
results, experiments we've tried, or just to keep more formal track of progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, this website will be another medium of communication for the club. I
will keep notes regarding meetings and post them here afterwards, so that anyone who
was unable to attend will know what was discussed, and if any links were
mentioned, those will be made generally available here. Additionally, meeting
notices and upcoming events will (eventually) be organized onto the
&lt;a href="schedule.html"&gt;schedule&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>